https://gifts.defenders.org/privacy-policy

Updated: May 25, 2018
The following websites (each a “Website” or “Site”, or together the “Websites” or “Sites”) are operated by Defenders of Wildlife (“Defenders”): www.Defenders.org, www.WildlifeAdoption.org, and www.DefendersBlog.org. Your privacy will be protected on these Websites in accordance with this privacy notice (“Privacy Notice”).
This Privacy Notice explains how Defenders collects and processes your Personal Data. Each time you use our Site, the current version of the Privacy Notice will apply. Accordingly,
whenever you use our Site, you should check the date of this Privacy Notice (which appears at the top) and review any changes since the last version. This Privacy Notice is applicable to all Site visitors, registered users, and all other users of our Site.
By visiting our Websites or using our mobile application you acknowledge that you have read and understood the processes and policies referred to in this Privacy Notice.
If you have questions regarding this Privacy Notice, please contact us by sending an email to privacy@defenders.org. You may also contact us via mail at:
Data Protection Officer
Defenders of Wildlife
National Headquarters
1130 17th Street, NW
Washington, DC 20036
For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), our Data Protection Officer is James Stofan who can be contacted by sending an email to privacy@defenders.org or by mail to:
Data Protection Officer
Defenders of Wildlife
National Headquarters
1130 17th Street, NW
Washington, DC 20036
Our Websites contains links to other third-party sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Websites and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.
A. Personal Information You May Choose to Provide:
In order to utilize certain features of our site or receive information from Defenders, you may choose to provide Personal Data. “Personal Data” is any information that enables us to identify you, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identifier such as your name, identification number, location data, online identifier or one or more factors specific to your, economic, cultural or social identity.
Personal Data that you give us
We may collect and process the following Personal Data:
Contact information (i.e., name, mailing and email address)
Demographic information (i.e., geographic location, gender, age, interests)
Membership information (donation amounts, open rate, action rate, event attendance)
Purchase information
Personal data we collect from you
With regard to each of your visits to the Site we will automatically collect the following information:
Technical information
Information about your visit
Location information
Non-Personal Data
We collect information that is sent to us automatically by your web browser and we may use this information to generate aggregate statistics about visitors to our Site, including, without limitation:
IP addresses
Browser type and plug-in details
Device type (e.g., desktop, laptop, tablet, phone, etc.)
Operating system
Local time zone
If you do submit Personal Data to us, we will use that information for the purposes for which it was submitted. We may also use your information in other ways, such as to contact you about other Defenders activities and/or fundraising campaigns or as otherwise disclosed to you at the point of collection. For example:
1. If you join our email list by registering for Defenders Wildlife eNews, we will have a record of your email address and all other information you choose to provide. We will send you Wildlife eNews and also may contact you with action alerts to save wildlife, fundraising campaigns, and other Defenders activities.
2. If you make an online donation to Defenders, your information will be added to our donor list and database, and you may be contacted about other Defenders activities, news, action alerts, and/or fundraising campaigns. Defenders may share our donor list (mailing addresses, only) with like-minded organizations. This provides you with the opportunity to learn about related activities of other nonprofit organizations. If you do not wish to have your information shared in this manner, please contact us at memberservices@defenders.org. Defenders will not share your email address, credit card or other personal information with other organizations.
3. If you join or opt-in to our activist network, you will receive informational updates and action alerts on wildlife and related issues. You also may be contacted about other Defenders activities, news, action alerts, and/or fundraising campaigns. Our activist network is an electronic network, and therefore we need an email address to contact you.
4. When you take an action such as sending a message to your elected representatives, government officials or other targets of Defenders advocacy, we will send your message to these recipients, along with the contact information you provide on the input form, typically including your name, address, and email address. Defenders is not responsible for what these recipients may do with your information. Please note that officials receiving these emails may choose to contact you. In addition, sometimes government agencies add the names of people who submit comments on government proposals into public documents recording the names of people who’ve commented in favor or opposed to a given proposal. This is often a part of the government process for receiving and recording feedback from the public. Government agencies typically have strict guidelines around not misusing information provided to them by the public for other purposes. However, you should review the policies of the appropriate government body if you are concerned.
5. We will receive any other information you choose to provide. For example, we may manage blogs or allow you to post stories or photos from time to time. By submitting such information to us, you give us permission to post it in the designated area on our Websites, edit it, or remove it if we deem that the content is not appropriate, outdated, etc. To protect your privacy, please do not include any identifying information when submitting blog entries or stories.
Defenders may contact you in a manner consistent with this Privacy Notice. You should be aware that we use third party vendors to provide services on our Websites and in our business operations. The information that you submit on our Websites may be provided to those vendors on a confidential basis so that those vendors can provide services (such as maintaining our database, sending email messages to activists, facilitating our fundraising activities and campaigns, purchasing tickets to our events, or processing credit card transactions) on our behalf.
We may share your Personal Data for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice with:
iWave (modeling)
Lexis Nexis (modeling)
NOZA (modeling)
FoundationSearch (modeling)
Instrumentl (modeling)
InfoGroup (modeling)
Abacus (modeling)
Apogee (modeling)
Donorbase (modeling)
I-Behavior (modeling)
Wiland (modeling)
Media IQ (modeling)
Luminate Online/Blackbaud (email and online donations)
Target Analytics/Blackbaud (analytics)
Mal Warwick|Donordirect (analytics)
Integral LLC (analytics)
Google (analytics)
Key Acquisition Partners (analytics)
Facebook (analytics and modeling)
Public Interest Communications (telemarketing)
SD&A (telemarketing)
Donor Services Group (telemarketing)
Alta Resources (fulfillment and member services)
RWT Production (campaign production)
Payment Solutions, Inc. (credit card processing)
Vantiv/World Pay (credit card processing)
Other than as described in this Privacy Notice, or as may be necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of our organization or others, or as may be necessary to comply with applicable law, Defenders will not give, share or sell the personal information you provide to us online.
Please note that Defenders occasionally shares some mailing address information with like-minded organizations. If you prefer that we not share your name or if you wish to modify communication, call 1-800-385-9712 or email us at memberservices@defenders.org. For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), Defenders does not share any data from EU countries or territories.
We maintain one or more databases to store your Personal Data and may keep such information indefinitely. For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), you do have the right to request that your record is permanently deleted from any and all of our databases.
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers.
The Personal Data that you povide to us is generally stored on servers located in the United States. If you are located in another jurisdiction, you should be aware that once your Personal Data is submitted through our Site, it will be transferred to our servers in the United States and that the United States currently does not have uniform data protection laws in place.
If you have questions regarding this Privacy Notice, please contact us by sending an email to privacy@defenders.org. You may also contact us via mail at:
Data Protection Officer
Defenders of Wildlife
National Headquarters
1130 17th Street, NW
Washington, DC 20036
For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), our Data Protection Officer is James Stofan who can be contacted by sending an email to privacy@defenders.org or by mail to:
Data Protection Officer
Defenders of Wildlife
National Headquarters
1130 17th Street, NW
Washington, DC 20036
B. Financial Information You May Choose to Provide:
If you choose to make an online donation to Defenders, you will have to provide your credit card billing information. As this information is collected and transferred over the Internet to our secure server, it is encrypted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, the industry standard security technology that is designed to protect sensitive information. Our donation pages display the Verisign Secure Site Seal to assure you that our Website is authentic and that all transactions are secured by SSL encryption. If you are making a donation, the credit card information that you provide at the time of donation is used only to process your donation and will not be used by us for any other purposes. For more information on our security policies, please see the "Security" section below.
C. Information We Automatically Collect and Store:
We automatically track and collect the following information when you visit our Websites: (i) IP address; (ii) domain server; (iii) type of computer; (iv) type of web browser; and (v) other logs (collectively "Traffic Data"). Traffic Data is anonymous information that does not personally identify you but is helpful for marketing purposes or for improving your experience on our Websites.
We also use "cookies" to customize content specific to your interests and to store your password, as applicable, so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit our Websites. A cookie is a piece of data stored on a visitor's hard drive to help us improve your access to our Websites and identify repeat visitors. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our Websites. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information on our Websites.
We use the following cookies:
Analytical/performance cookies
Functionality cookies
Targeting cookies
Third-party cookies
You do not have to accept our cookies and can block them by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse all or some cookies. You may also delete them after they have been placed on your hard drive. If you do not accept or delete our cookies, some areas of the Site that you access may take more time to work, or may not function properly. For more information about cookies, visit: http://www.allaboutcookies.org.
We support “do not track” signals (“DNT”). If you have DNT enabled in your web browser, we will not receive browser-related information from our advertising partners for tailoring advertisements.
For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), Defenders does not add cookies to EU country or territory IP addresses to collect PPI.
For more information, please see our Cookie Policy.
D. Security:
Our Websites have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. The security measures used on our Websites include, but are not limited to, industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, Verisign certificates, firewalls, and internal policies to maintain the security of stored data. While we follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is completely secure. Many breaches of security occur when users are not vigilant in protecting their own information. The next section of our Privacy Notice suggests some actions you can take to help control the security of your personal information.
E. Your Help Is Needed:
Although Defenders does its best to protect your privacy, you can help in the following ways:
You have control over your own privacy. Think carefully before providing any personal information.
Although our Websites have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control, no email or Internet transmission is completely secure against interception. If you are worried because your communication is very sensitive, do not send it via email or submit it online. You may call us at 1-800-385-9712, or contact us via mail at:
Donor Services
Defenders of Wildlife
National Headquarters
1130 17th Street, NW
Washington, DC 20036
3. Remember that we cannot protect your privacy once you leave our Websites, such as by "hyperlink." When you visit other websites including shopping/e-commerce sites affiliated with Defenders but managed by third party organizations, check each site's privacy Notice yourself, and be careful about the information you offer up.
4. We may send you personalized information via email or provide personalized links in emails that allow data fields to be automatically populated with certain personal information. Therefore, you should always keep your email account information secure and not allow others to access your email account.
F. How to Unsubscribe or Contact Defenders About Your Information:
If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice send an email to: privacy@defenders.org.
Correction and removal
If any of the information that we have about you is incorrect, would like to stop receiving email from us in the future, need to update your email or other contact information, or you wish to have information (including Personal Data) removed from our records, please contact us at memberservices@defenders.org.
Opting Out
Additionally, if you prefer not to receive marketing messages from us, please let us know by clicking on the unsubscribe link within any marketing message that you receive, or by sending a message to us at memberservices@defenders.org.
For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (the “GDPR”), our Data Protection Officer is James Stofan who can be contacted by sending an email to privacy@defenders.org or by mail to:
Data Protection Officer
Defenders of Wildlife
National Headquarters
1130 17th Street, NW
Washington, DC 20036
Your European Rights
You have the right to ask us not to process your Personal Data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your Personal Data) if we intend to use your Personal Data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can also exercise the right by contacting us using the Contact Us section on our Site.
Under European data protection law, in certain circumstances, you have the right to:
Request access to your Personal Data
Request correction of your Personal Data
Request erasure of your Personal Data
Object to processing of your Personal Data
Request restriction of processing your Personal Data
Request transfer of your Personal Data
Withdraw your consent
In addition, where you believe that Defenders has not complied with its obligations under this Privacy Notice or European law, you have the right to make a complaint to an EU Data Protection Authority, such as the UK Information Commissioner’s Office.
Your Californian Rights
California law imposes very specific requirements for Site users residing in California requiring certain businesses to disclose policies relating to sharing certain categories of your Personal Data with third parties.
FOR RESIDENTS OF CALIFORNIA ONLY. Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code requires select businesses to disclose policies relating to the sharing of certain categories of your Personal Data with third parties. If you reside in California and have provided your Personal Data, you may request information about our disclosures of certain categories of Personal Data to third parties for direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us at one of the following addresses: privacy@defenders.org or by mail to:
Data Protection Officer
Attn: California Privacy Rights
Defenders of Wildlife
1130 17th Street, NW
Washington, DC 20036
G. Children's Privacy:
Our Websites are not intended for children, and we do not knowingly collect or use any personally identifiable information from online visitors under 13 years of age. If we learn that Personal Data of persons less than 13 years-of-age has been collected through our Site, we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.
H. Updates and Changes to Privacy Notice:
We reserve the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Notice, simply by posting such change, update or modification on our Websites. Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon posting on our Websites. Therefore, it is important that you periodically review this Privacy Notice.
If we make any material changes to this Privacy Notice or the way we use, share or collect personal Data, we will notify you by revising the “Effective Date” at the top of this Privacy Notice, prominently posting an announcement of the changes on our Site, or sending an email to the email address you most recently provided us (unless we do not have such an email address) prior to the new policy taking effect. Any changes we make to our Privacy Notice in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notification sent to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Privacy Notice.
